A package is the next level of
organization above a module Remember that a
module is usually one Python file A
package is usually a folder that groups
related Python modules together Imagine that you
are building a larger analytics project You
might have one module for finance calculations
one module for health-related calculations and one
module for reporting tools Instead of leaving
all of those files loose in the
main project folder you can group them
inside a package folder This makes the
project structure easier to understand When someone
looks at the folder they can immediately
see which files belong together Traditionally Python
packages often contain a special file named
dunder init dot P Y Modern Python
can support some package structures without that
file but you will still see dunder
init dot P Y in many real
projects For this introductory module you do
not need to build a complicated package
The main goal is to understand the
hierarchy A module is generally one file
A package is a folder of related
modules A library is a broader collection
of reusable tools that may contain multiple
packages and modules Later when we use
libraries such as NumPy and Pandas this
terminology will make more sense because you
will see how large collections of Python
tools are organized